Bryan bhipps72@gmail.com Hipps

Charleston, SC

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Bryan-bhipps72%40gmail-com-Hipps/ b67cb45c08d428d7

Talented and Highly Motivated RF Engineer with an extensive background in CDMA Network Design and System Performance. Over 18 years of experience in the wireless telephony field. Strengths include the ability to motivate an Engineering staff to excellence in Network Design and Optimization and the application of creative solutions to tough design and network performance problems. Expeirenced in Lucent,

Motorola, and Erriccson equipment and engineering.

Work Experience

Lead RF Engineer

Airgate PCS/Alamosa PCS/Sprint PCS - Charleston, SC February 2021 to April 2021

· Responsible for the design, implementation, performance management, and optimization of Sprint's CDMA network in Charleston and Myrtle Beach, SC, encompassing over 200 Cell Sites. Insure Performance Indicators are monitored and prioritize work activities based on quality measurements. Supervise vendor (Lucent) personnel in New Site Turn Up operations and performed daily optimization of network resulting in an Overall Network Drop and Block percentage of <0.5%

Daily Average. Trained other personnel in various groups on usage of tools such as Invex/Grayson, Prospect, Planet EV, Wiltron, HP Spectrum Analyzer, and In House

Tools to assist in daily Network Improvement and Troubleshooting. Created various tools which are used in Daily Network Optimization efforts.

Senior RF Engineer

Leap Wireless-ATT/Charleston - Raleigh, NC August 2020 to April 2021

 \cdot Responsible for the design, implementation, performance management, and optimization of the Cricket Wireless CDMA network in Charleston, SC, as well as

Macon, Ga, Raleigh, NC and Columbus, Ga. encompassing well over 200 cell sites.

Insure Performance Indicators are monitored and prioritize work activities based on quality measurements. Supervised several Tiger Teams for market improvements and performance improvements. Supervise vendor (Nortel) personnel in New Site Turn

Up operations and performed daily optimization of network. Trained other personnel in various groups on usage of tools such as Invex/Grayson, Prospect, Planet EV,

Wiltron, HP Spectrum Analyzer, and In House Tools to assist in daily Network

Improvement and Troubleshooting. Created various tools which are used in Daily

Network Optimization efforts. Insurmental in reducing overall Drop% and Block% in all markets to <.50% within one year of start date. Extremely aggressive and successful in all network optimization.

Crawlspace Medic Charleston-CEO January 2019 to March 2021

Responsible for all aspects of Crawlspace business. Sales, Marketing, Project management, ordering materials, jobs, etc. etc. Completed various crawlspace jobs to include, structural repairs, moisture remediation, sump pump installs, dehumidifier installs, etc. etc.

RF Engineer/Senior RF Engineer

January 2021 to February 2021

 \cdot Assisted in Managing the Coastal RF Engineering staff. Worked with an Engineering group which designed and optimized a CDMA Network for coastal NC, SC,

& GA. Responsible for all aspects of RF Design including site selection, compliance, capacity planning, PN planning, and network optimization. Designed

In-Building repeater implementations for small and large customers. Optimized network to maintain a high degree of customer satisfaction using both network performance statistics and real time drive data collection tools. Interfaced effectively with both the equipment vendor (Lucent) to stay abreast of technology issues, and various other groups within Airgate/Alamosa, such as Site Development,

Senior RF Field Technician

December 1999 to January 2021

· Assisted in Managing the Vendor (Lucent) in initial Network Build for the

Eastern NC Markets, to include, Wilmington, Jacksonville, New Bern, Goldsboro,

Greenville, Rocky Mount, Roanoke Rapids, and Outer Banks. Responsible for the initial Network Build and Optimization of all Eastern, NC Markets, resulting in a

Network Commercial Launch 6 months ahead of schedule. Responsible for all aspects of Daily Network Performance in Eastern NC Markets. Responded and Rectified

Trouble Tickets, Performed all new site Field Responsibilities including, antenna and line sweeps, T1 Testing, New Site Turn Up, 911 Testing, Field Drive Testing, and assisted in testing including site selection, compliance, capacity planning,

PN planning, and network optimization.

CEO/Owner

LT Development

September 2015 to September 2015

Responsible for purchasing, renovating, and selling of investment homes. Worked with contracors on all aspects of repairs. Worked with Realtors in buying and selling of homes.

CEO/Owner

New Homes Connection August 2005 to August 2005

Licensed Realtor since 2005. Worked with various people in buying and selling homes.

RF Cellular Field Engineer

Motorola - Raleigh, NC

March 1997 to December 1999

· Provided RF, Cell Site, and Performance support to Various Carriers nationwide for Motorola's Digital and Analog Cellular Systems. Was responsible for RF System design, implementation and optimization of both Analog and CDMA networks. Tasks included training personnel in all aspects of cellular system design and optimization, statistics collection and interpretation, and hardware troubleshooting. Was responsible for maintaining a high level of customer satisfaction. Managed system RF drive teams, Cell Site Contractors, and data processing personnel.

· Recognized with "Outstanding Achievement" Award.

System Engineer

US Army-Multi Channel Communications October 1989 to March 1997

Communications Engineer

· Designed, Optimized, and Operated 1900 MHz UHF/VHF Mobile Subscriber Network

Systems. Deployed Networks using GTE Mobile Subscriber Equipment Systems. Involved in the initial government launch of the first CDMA Based communications systems both overseas and stateside. Trained in all aspects of CDMA System implementation, optimization and operation.

· Sep 2006 – Feb 2007: Group leader of Communications Group Deployed to Bosnia in support of Operation Joint Endeavor. Was responsible for providing over 20,000

Lines of Mobile Phone Service to various United States Military, Civilian, and

Government entities. Responsible for timely turnup and integration of new cells.

Education

Business

University of Maryland 1993 to 1997

Central Texas College

1993 to 1997

Etowah High School - Woodstock, GA 1986 to 1989

Skills

- Computer operation
- Software testing
- Microsoft Access
- Computer skills
- Analysis skills
- Solaris
- Driving
- System design
- Microsoft Word
- UNIX
- Operating systems
- 3G
- Microsoft Excel
- · Computer networking